<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>c.q. blog</title>
<link>https://econ-gis.github.io/</link>
<atom:link href="https://econ-gis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>A blog by a Japanese PhD student in Economics based in Switzerland</description>
<generator>quarto-1.5.57</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 22:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Complain not to complain</title>
  <link>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0619_complain/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><br>
</p>
<p>Lately, I’ve been feeling a bit uncomfortable in my work environment.</p>
<p>Let me start by acknowledging that this post might sound like a complaint in itself. That’s not my intention. I just want to think through this quietly.</p>
<p>There’s someone around me who complains about something almost every few hours. What makes me uncomfortable is not just the frequency, but the nature of the complaints. Usually, they’re not about things that cause real problems, reduce anyone’s welfare, or make our work environment worse. Instead, they tend to be cultural frustrations—things that are simply different from what they’re used to. A common phrase is something like, “That’s not how we do it in my country,” followed by “That’s crazy” or “I hate it.” The tone feels too harsh to me, and I’m not used to that kind of reaction. To me, it just seems like a lack of openness to difference.</p>
<p>Of course, I complain sometimes too. But I try to stay aware of it and keep it in check. I try to be mindful of when and how I express frustration. As far as I know, I don’t complain like that in front of non-Japanese people, at least, and I don’t initiate those kinds of conversations. If someone asks, I might say something like, “Yeah, I miss clean toilets and good seafood.” That sort of thing.</p>
<p>This person also tends to react emotionally, even to small things. They get upset or overwhelmed quickly. It makes it hard to respond with kindness. Maybe I don’t have to. I’m not sure. But by nature, I can’t completely ignore it—unless I decide to stop talking to them altogether, which feels like a last resort.</p>
<p>People often say that you become the average of the five people around you. It’s not easy to control who you spend time with, especially when you’re living in a foreign country and doing a PhD.</p>
<p>I don’t feel contaminated yet, but I’m uncomfortable being in an environment where that could happen, quietly, and without me even noticing. It’s not just emotional discomfort; it’s the possibility of gradually absorbing a way of thinking, speaking, or relating to others that I don’t want to make my own. Just like how spending too much time around unhealthy friendships can slowly shift your mindset, I don’t want to let myself drift in that direction.</p>
<p>At the same time, I know that in western cultures, people are often encouraged to express their needs or preferences more directly than in Japan. Still, I don’t feel it’s my place to tell someone to complain less. That doesn’t feel like my role. If I truly cared about this person, I would probably speak up. But I don’t think I do in this case.</p>
<p>Even if I’m right in thinking that “constantly complaining is not ideal for social life,” I don’t feel motivated to invest my energy in trying to help them change.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading this far.<br>
(∗ ˊωˋ ∗)</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>research</category>
  <guid>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0619_complain/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nobody cites my paper</title>
  <link>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0607_citation/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My friend’s paper, published in 2023, has already been cited over 20 times.</p>
<p>My own paper, published in 2024, has only been cited twice. The literature is quite niche, but if my paper had been published a few years earlier (first submission was in 2021), I’m fairly confident it would have received 5–10 citations or even more by now because the seminal work in this field seems to have emerged around that time.</p>
<p>It took me, yes, a very, very long time.</p>
<p>(And just to note: his paper was published in a more recognized journal than mine.)</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>research</category>
  <guid>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0607_citation/</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Starting a blog</title>
  <link>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0605_starting_blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><br>
</p>
<section id="why-write" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="why-write">Why write?</h2>
<p>I enjoy writing short texts every day. <br> Until recently, I’ve been using Twitter/X for that. But I wanted a space to write in more complete sentences, without thinking about followers.</p>
<p>And, I don’t want to post on my personal website. There are people who view blogging with skepticism, and since I’m in a position where visibility can shape evaluations and outcomes, I’d rather not draw unnecessary attention.</p>
</section>
<section id="what-to-expect" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-to-expect">What to expect</h2>
<p>Topics will likely orbit around:</p>
<ul>
<li>What everyday life feels like as a foreigner, non-European, a PhD student, and an imposter</li>
<li>Empirical work in environmental and development economics</li>
<li>Spatial and remote sensing data (analysis)</li>
<li>Efficient/reproducible project management (e.g., Git(Hub), <code>{renv}</code>, <code>{targets}</code>) that I enjoy</li>
<li>Notes or summaries from articles I read (kind of like TILs)</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="what-not-to-expect" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-not-to-expect">What not to expect</h2>
<p>If you find something useful here, great. <br> If not, that’s fine too.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://econ-gis.github.io/posts/2025/0605_starting_blog/</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
